翻译 Linn 右翼部鸣明 校对 牙牙 Husky聚聚
时间轴 SG 文本处理 谷子 yoyo
资源搬运 yoyo
再见 感谢光临
Bye!Thanks for coming!
嘿 又是两位顾客
Man, two customers!
自从15年前的泥浆龙卷风以来
The car wash hasn't been that busy
洗车的工作从未如此忙过
since that mud tornado 15 years ago.
人们称之为“泥龙卷”
They called it "The mud-nado."
哇！你在在这里工作的时间比我活过的时间还要长！
Wow! You've worked here longer than I've been alive!
你是怎么得到这份工作的？
How'd you even get this job?
嗯，当时我正和你妈妈处对象，然后....
Well, I was hanging out with your mom, and --
等等！
Hold the phone!
噢，你的动作真快
Oh, you're getting fast there.
不要直接讲给我，唱给我听！
Don't tell me, sing me!
淘气鬼！
You rascal!
下次我给你讲故事的时候 能用唱歌以外的方式吗？
Can I ever tell you a story without working in a song again?
我边听边学
I'm playing it by ear.
你，瞧瞧你自己
♪ You, look at everything you are ♪
瞧瞧那些因你而起的美好
♪ Look at everything you do
真是难以置信
♪ It's incredible
就如你一般像是奇迹
♪ As incredible as you
至于我
♪ And me
我想我已经满足于
♪ I guess I'm content to be
投入奇迹般的你
♪ On the arm of someone who
的怀抱
♪ Is as incredible as you
崇拜你的激励与振奋人心
♪ And it's a full-time job admiring ♪
是我的全部事业
♪ All the ways that you're inspiring ♪
如果可以
♪ If I had my way
我会固执地坚持
♪ I'd do it all day
那就是为何我难以开口提出
♪ That's why it's really, really hard to say ♪
我想我需要一点改变
♪ I think I need a little cha-a-ange ♪
♪ I think I need a little cha-a-a-a-a-a-a-ange ♪
我一直相信
♪ I always did believe
只要有爱
♪ That love is all you need
就可以做一个幸福的人
♪ To be a happy man
这听上去可能有点幼稚
♪ That may have been naive
但是我想我还需要食物
♪ I guess I need to eat
这不在计划之内
♪That wasn't in the plan
崇拜你的激励与振奋人心
♪ And it's a full-time job admiring ♪
是我的全部事业
♪ All the ways that you're inspiring ♪
如果可以
♪ If I had my way
我会固执地坚持
♪ I'd do it all day
唯一的问题是这样一点也赚不到
♪ The only problem is it doesn't pay ♪
我想我需要一点零钱
♪ I think I need a little cha-a-ange ♪
♪ I think I need a little cha-a-a-a-a-a-ange ♪
噢 这些都不够买一个坏掉的热狗
Oh, that's not even enough for a bad hot dog.
嘿哟 维达利亚
Sup, Vidalia?
葛瑞格
Greg...
真是个惊喜喔
What a surprise.
准备好开吃了吗？
Ready to eat?
你会爱上这些萝卜泥的
You're gonna love these mushed up carrots!
某人开始激动了哦
Someone's excited!
准备好了吗
Get ready.
噢 你酷到不吃萝卜泥了
Oh, you're too cool for mushed up carrots?
我饿死了
I'm hungry for babies!
嘿 我这正忙着喂孩子呢！
Hey, I'm trying to negotiate here.
噢 你这里有好吃的
Ooh! You got the good stuff.
难道你那神奇女友不会做饭吗？
Doesn't your magical girlfriend know how to cook?
嗯哼，玫瑰根本不需要进食 但我需要
Nah, Rose doesn't really need to eat, but I do.
除了整天崇拜你女友
Hmm. So have you done anything lately --
你最近都干了些啥
besides worship everything she does?
我已经为我的新专辑写了好几首歌了
I've been working on some songs for my new album.
噢，就是那张
Oh, the same new album
你准备了六个月的新专辑
you've been working on for six months?
是的
Yep!
喔，那真是不错
Oh, that's good.
你的妈咪生活过得怎样？
How's baby life?
看起来如何？
How does it look?
辛苦
Hard.
你介意在我在你这白吃吗?
Mind if I bum around here for the day?
我已经习惯了
No more than usual.
你真是吊起了我的胃口  宇宙
Man, you're really selling me on that cereal, Universe.
啊这东西真好吃
It's so good!
到妈妈这儿来
Come to mama.
谢谢你给我留下的残渣 葛瑞格
Thanks for leaving me all the cereal dust, Greg!
不用谢
No problem!
呃，现在我该吃些什么呢
Ugh! What am I supposed to eat now?
真是好主意，酸奶油
Oh, good idea, Sour Cream!
今年秋季上映
Coming this fall --
他是个有着大风范的小管家
He's a little butler with a big attitude.
维达利亚 你以前看过这个喜剧没....
Vidalia, have you seen this com--
我的沙发！
Whoa!My couch!
我想我把这里弄脏了，是吧？
I guess I made a mess, huh?
慢着 赶紧把衣服脱了
Uhp-uhp! Take it off.
哦对 抱歉
Oh, yeah, sorry.
哇哦，这衣服不错
Whoa, that's a look.
哪里来的？
Where'd you get that shirt?
体恤店呗
T-shirt shop.
你买了这件体恤？
You bought that?
不这是我的工作制服
No, it's my uniform.
我从今天开始在这上班了
I work there starting today.
这可有点不像你噢
You sold out, V.
人有时也需要成长的
Got to grow up sometime.
喂？
Hello?
嗯.....
Uh-huh.
等等，你不能来了是什么意思
Wait, what do you meanyou can't come?
有家人去世了
Death in the family?
等等 只是一只仓鼠死了可不能算
Wait, a hamster doesn't count!
你不能这样对待我
You can't do this to me!
听着 我..我真的需要...
Look, I -- I really need --
嘿 喂 人呢？
Hey! Hello?
真是讨厌的小孩子
Lousy 12-year-old!
怎么回事
What happened?
听好了葛瑞格 我的保姆来不了
Listen, Greg, my babysitter cancelled.
我需要你在我工作的时候帮我照看酸奶油
I need you to watch Sour Cream for me while I'm at work.
你能帮我吗
Can you do it?
噢 当然 为什么不能呢
Oh, yeah. Why not?
我平时也无事可做
I'm not doing anything.
应该是吧...
I think.
相信我 你整天都闲的慌
Trust me, you're not.
好了 不要忘记尿布包放在那儿
Okay, don't forget, diaper bag's over there,
零食放在这儿的
snacks are over there.
应急号码贴在冰箱上的
Emergency number's on the fridge.
还有 如果我的孩子出了什么意外
And if anything bad happens to my kid,
那你最好祈祷你的宇宙神奇女友
you better pray your space goddess' magic
有起死回生的能力
can bring people back from the dead,
因为我会灭了你
because I will destroy you.
...工作愉快
Have fun at work.
好了，怎么样酸奶油
So, how about it, Sour Cream,
准备好和你潇洒的叔叔度过一天吗
you ready to spend the day with your rad Unkie Greg?
你可真像维达利亚啊 不是吗
You really are Vidalia's son, aren't you?
好啦
There you go.
小酸奶油 来见识一下防晒霜
Okay. Baby Sour Cream,meet sun screen.
噢 不能忘了这个
Oh, can't forget these!
你真是个炫酷的小孩儿
You're one cool baby!
嗨 葛瑞格
Hi, Greg!
嗨 玫瑰
Hi, Rose.
葛瑞格
Greg!
这个小型人类是在哪里找来的
Where did you get this mini human from?
噢 这是酸奶油
Oh, this is Sour Cream.
是你把他制造出来的吗
Did you make him?
啥？
Wh-what?
不是 我只是在帮维达利亚带孩子
No. I'm just babysitting for Vidalia.
嗨 酸奶油
Hi, Sour Cream.
我是玫瑰
I'm Rose.
嘿 我们来教他怎样正确地在沙滩嗨吧
Hey, let's show this baby how to beach it.
好啊
Yeah!
真是太棒了
That feels great!
嘿 酸奶油 看这边
Hey, Sour Cream,look at me.
我是个沙人
I'm a sand man!
我想他大概就是喜欢干坐在这块毯子上吧
I guess he just likes siting on this blanket.
你绝对不会猜到我花了多长时间
You wouldn't believe how long it took me to figure out
才弄明白他和你是同类
that this and you are the same thing.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你们都是人类
You're both human.
得承认 这挺令人迷惑的
You have to admit,it's a little confusing.
你长得比较高大 可以说话
Your big and can talk,
他长得小得多 而且只会咿咿呀呀
and he's small and can only make noises.
我怎么会想到你们是一个物种呢
How was I supposed to know you were the same species?
怎么了
What?
我知道这听起来挺傻气的
I know, it's silly.
但是后来我注意到你会成长
But then I started to notice that you grow.
嘛 我要是只有和婴儿一样大的手可玩不了吉他啊
Well, can't play guitar with little baby hands.
每一个宝石人的诞生都是目的性的
When a gem is made,it's for a reason.
当她们从土里出来的那一刻起
They burst out of the ground
就已经知晓自己的使命
already knowing what they're supposed to be, and then...
而那就是她们一辈子注定的
that's what they are.
命运了
Forever.
但是你呢 注定会有所改变
But you, you're supposed to change.
每时每刻的你都是不一样的
You're never the same even moment to moment --
人们允许并支持你走自己想要的路
you're allowed and expected to invent who you are.
可以“成长”的能力--这是多么不可思议的力量啊
What an incredible power --the ability to "grow up."
这些话写进歌词一定不错
Those would make
some pretty good lyrics.
等一下 帮我看一会儿酸奶油
Hold on. Watch Sour Cream a second.
我要把那些话写下来
I got to write this down!
好了 你刚才都说了些什么
All right, what were you saying?
那些深奥但也还算雅俗共赏的玩意儿
Something really profound,yet relatable?
天了噜 维达利亚会灭了我的
Oh, my gosh!Vidalia is gonna destroy me!
酸奶油
Sour Cream!
玫瑰
Rose!
你们在哪
Where are you guys?!
玫瑰
Rose!
酸奶油
Sour cream?!
你们在这里吗
Are y'all up there?!
酸奶油
Sour Cream!
玫瑰奶油
Rose cream!
玫瑰
Rose?!
葛瑞格
Greg.
玫瑰
Rose!
哇 你看起来非常疲惫
Wow, you look tired.
谢天谢地 我终于找到你们两 --
Thank goodness I found
the both --
酸奶油呢
Where's Sour Cream?!
我以为你已经答应了帮我看着他
I thought you were gonna watch him for me!
我有看着他啊
Oh, I watched him.
我一直看着他爬到了…
I watched him climb all the way...
那里
up there.
∑(っ °Д °;)っ
这不是很刺激吗
Isn't this exciting?
对他来说一定是一次建设性的体验
This'll be a formative experience for him.
如果他掉下来就不会是了
Well, not if he falls!
快来
Come on!
好的
Okay.
我会试着把他抱下来
I'll try and get him down.
嘿 小酸奶油 坐着别动
Hey, Baby Cream,stay right there.
你是怎么能够这么淡定的
How can you be so calm right now?
呃 我要怎么下…
Uh... How do I get...
玫瑰
Rose!
救我下来
Help me out!
那儿是不是有控制台
Are those the controls over there?
对 是的 坚持一下
Right, yes. Hold on.
我觉得你得拉一下某个操纵杆
I think you got to pull one of those levers!
这个吗
This one?
喔啊 现在 呃 转的有点太快了
Whoa! It's, uh, going a little too fast.
坚持住啊 酸奶油
Hold on, Sour Cream.
玫瑰 快把我从这作孽的玩意上救下来啊
Rose, get me off this crazy thing!
呃啊 给我放开葛瑞格
Ugh!Leave Greg alone!
不-误-误-误——
No-o-o-o-o-o!
葛瑞格
Greg!
Greg.
酸奶油
Sour Cream!
呼 还好他没事
Whew!He's safe.
你为什么会让他爬那个东西
Why did you let him climb that thing?
他想爬啊
He wanted to.
玫瑰 你不能任由他随心所欲地做事
Well, Rose, you can't just let him do whatever he wants.
但是你不也是这样的吗 而且你也挺好的
But you do whatever you want, and you're fine.
确实 但是我不是一个小孩儿啊
Yeah, but I'm not a baby.
我不用别人来喂我或者帮我换衣服
I don't need someone to feed me or change my clothes
当我爬上个摩天轮
I don't need someone to save me
我也不需要别人来救…
when I climb on to a Ferris wheel and...
诶玛
Oh, man.
我就是个小孩儿
I'm a baby.
你想现在下来吗
Do you want to get down?
嗯
Yeah.
噢 看看你自己 跟葛瑞格玩的开心吗 酸奶油
Aw, look at you. Did you have fun with Greg, Sour Cream?
当然
Oh, yeah.
在葛瑞格叔叔身边 只有安全健康的欢乐
Nothing but safe wholesome fun with Unkie Greg.
听着 维达利亚
Listen, Vidalia,
呃 谢谢你提供的食物和其他东西
um, thanks for the food and everything else.
今天一天我过得非常充实
Today has been quite a journey.
好…吧
Okay?
你的衣服已经洗干净了
Your shirt's clean.
你是要拿回来 还是想就这么
You want it back,or are you just gonna go
赤膊漫步？
for a topless stroll?
嘿 有时候我们总要长大的 是吧
Hey, we all got to grow up sometime, right?
答非所问是几个意思
That's not really relevant to my question.
我知道我身材不高
♪ I know I'm not that tall
我知道我没有聪明绝顶
♪ I know I'm not that smart
让我驾着货车驶入你的洗车间
♪ Let me drive my van into your wash ♪
哇 所以从此你就在这里工作了
Wow. And you've worked here ever since.
没错
That's right.
你懂的 不管愿意与否 人都是要长大的
You know, people grow,whether they want to or not.
但是成长也是一个人必须做出的决定
But growing up is something you got to decide to do.
嘿 那小酸奶油又是怎么成长的
Hey, what ever happened to Baby Sour Cream?
没有人知道
No one knows.